Dean Cohen

1928 S. Division Avenue, Boise, ID 83706 www.deancohen.site | | deancohen@u.boisestate.edu

Technical Skills:

Languages: C/C++, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ActionScript 3.0, ShaderLab.

Software Experience: Unreal, Unity, Adobe Creative Suite, Visual Studio 2015/2017, GitHub,

Microsoft Office, Blender, Maya.

Gameplay Programming: Implementation of gameplay systems and logic in both C++ and C#, including player controls and movement, game mode creation, spawning systems, use of vector math, and basic AI functionality.

Misc: Extensive experience working with Oculus VR in Unity. Experience with mobile development to Android. Experience in developing for Microsoft HoloLens and 360 video. **Team Experience:** Worked on a number of teams of artists and programmers on multi-year projects, taking on roles such as lead programmer, game designer and artist.

Game Projects:

Title: Lexicon (2017-2018)

Roles: Lead Programmer, Lead Designer, Lead Artist

Description: A VR Multiplayer Cooperative Puzzle game with one player in VR and the other not

in VR. Year-long project completed completely independently.

Engine: Unity (C#)

Title: Wizards of Siegerly Place (2018-Present)

Roles: Lead Programmer

Description: A Multiplayer FPS game with magic combat. This is an ongoing project made with a

3-person team. Currently been in development for 6 months.

Engine: Unreal (C++)

Work Experience:

GIMM Dev Team Developer - Boise State University (12/2016 - Present): Work as a main programmer for various games and interactive media pieces including creating VR interaction systems with Touch and other controls, self-contained puzzle mechanics, custom shaders, and vector-based movement and effects.

Game Programmer – Bion Studio (10/2016 – 10/2017): Developed gameplay systems for various projects including a dynamic alchemy system, soft-body physics, and procedural music. Student Lab Technician - Idaho National Laboratory (2/2016 - 12/2016): Developed augmented reality app that procedurally visualizes density data for nuclear control rods.

Education:

Graduating 5/2019 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Gaming, Interactive Media and Mobile Technology/Minor in Psychology - Boise State University Dean's list with highest honors - 3.9 G.P.A.

Miscellaneous:

Favorite Games: Hollow Knight, Elder Scrolls 5: Skyrim, Rainbow Six: Siege, Overwatch, Paper Mario and the Thousand Year Door, Darksiders 2, Dishonored 2, Ark: Survival Evolved.